<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?><bugrepository name="CASSANDRA">
  
  
  <bug fixdate="2018-1-12 01:00:00" id="14931" opendate="2018-12-12 00:00:00" resolution="Fixed">
    <buginformation>
      <summary>Backport In-JVM dtests to 2.2, 3.0 and 3.11</summary>
      <description>The In-JVM dtests are of significant value, and much of the testing we are exploring with it can easily be utilised on all presently maintained versions. We should backport the functionality to at least 3.0.x and 3.11.x - and perhaps even consider 2.2.</description>
      <version>2.2.14,3.0.18,3.11.4</version>
      <fixedVersion>Test/dtest/java</fixedVersion>
      <type>Improvement</type>
    </buginformation>
    <fixedFiles>
      <file type="M">test.distributed.org.apache.cassandra.distributed.LegacyAdapter.java</file>
    </fixedFiles>
  </bug>
  <bug fixdate="2019-1-7 01:00:00" id="14956" opendate="2019-1-7 00:00:00" resolution="Fixed">
    <buginformation>
      <summary>Paged Range Slice queries with DISTINCT can drop rows from results</summary>
      <description>If we have a partition where the first CQL row is fully deleted (possibly via TTLs), and that partition happens to fall on the page boundary of a paged range query which is using SELECT DISTINCT, the next live partition after it is omitted from the result set. This is due to over fetching of the pages and a bug in trimming those pages where overlap occurs.This does not affect 3.0+.</description>
      <version>2.1.21,2.2.14</version>
      <fixedVersion>CQL/Interpreter</fixedVersion>
      <type>Bug</type>
    </buginformation>
    <fixedFiles>
      <file type="M">src.java.org.apache.cassandra.service.pager.RangeSliceQueryPager.java</file>
      <file type="M">src.java.org.apache.cassandra.service.pager.AbstractQueryPager.java</file>
      <file type="M">CHANGES.txt</file>
      <file type="M">test.unit.org.apache.cassandra.cql3.PagingTest.java</file>
      <file type="M">test.conf.cassandra-murmur.yaml</file>
    </fixedFiles>
  </bug>
  <bug fixdate="2019-1-15 01:00:00" id="14985" opendate="2019-1-15 00:00:00" resolution="Fixed">
    <buginformation>
      <summary>CircleCI docker image should bake in more dependencies</summary>
      <description>It's pretty frequent especially in the upgrade tests for either maven or github to fail. I think they are detecting the thundering herd of containers all pulling stuff at the same time and opting out.We can reduce this especially for maven dependencies since most are hardly ever changing by downloading everything we can in advance and baking it into the image.When building the docker image Initialize the local maven repository by running ant maven-ant-tasks-retrieve-build for 2.1-trunk and do the same with CCM and the Apache repository.</description>
      <version>2.2.14,3.0.18,3.11.4,4.0-alpha1,4.0</version>
      <fixedVersion>CI,Test/dtest/python,Test/unit</fixedVersion>
      <type>Improvement</type>
    </buginformation>
    <fixedFiles>
      <file type="M">CHANGES.txt</file>
      <file type="M">.circleci.config.yml</file>
    </fixedFiles>
  </bug>
</bugrepository>