<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<bugrepository name="HBASE">
  <bug id="10335" opendate="2014-1-14 00:00:00" fixdate="2014-1-14 01:00:00" resolution="Fixed">
    <buginformation>
      <summary>AuthFailedException in zookeeper may block replication forever</summary>
      <description>ReplicationSource will rechoose sinks when encounted exceptions during skipping edits to the current sink. But if the zookeeper client for peer cluster go to AUTH_FAILED state, the ReplicationSource will always get AuthFailedException. The ReplicationSource does not reconnect the peer, because reconnectPeer only handle ConnectionLossException and SessionExpiredException. As a result, the replication will print log: 2014-01-14,12:07:06,892 INFO org.apache.hadoop.hbase.replication.regionserver.ReplicationSource: Getting 0 rs from peer cluster # 202014-01-14,12:07:06,892 INFO org.apache.hadoop.hbase.replication.regionserver.ReplicationSource: Slave cluster looks down: 20 has 0 region serversand be blocked forever.I think other places may have same problems for not handling AuthFailedException in zookeeper. eg: HBASE-8675.apurtell</description>
      <version>0.94.15,0.99.0</version>
      <fixedVersion>0.98.0,0.96.2,0.99.0,0.94.17</fixedVersion>
      <type>Bug</type>
    </buginformation>
    <fixedFiles>
      <file type="M">hbase-client.src.main.java.org.apache.hadoop.hbase.replication.ReplicationPeersZKImpl.java</file>
    </fixedFiles>
  </bug>
  <bug id="10366" opendate="2014-1-16 00:00:00" fixdate="2014-1-16 01:00:00" resolution="Fixed">
    <buginformation>
      <summary>0.94 filterRow() may be skipped in 0.96(or onwards) code</summary>
      <description>HBASE-6429 combines both filterRow &amp; filterRow(List&lt;KeyValue&gt; kvs) functions in Filter. While 0.94 code or older, it may not implement hasFilterRow as HBase-6429 expected because 0.94(old) hasFilterRow only returns true when filterRow(List&lt;KeyValue&gt; kvs) is overridden not the filterRow(). Therefore, the filterRow() will be skipped.Since we don't ask 0.94 users to update their existing filter code, the issue will cause scan returns unexpected keyvalues and break the backward compatibility.</description>
      <version>None</version>
      <fixedVersion>0.98.0,0.96.2</fixedVersion>
      <type>Bug</type>
    </buginformation>
    <fixedFiles>
      <file type="M">hbase-server.src.test.java.org.apache.hadoop.hbase.filter.TestFilter.java</file>
      <file type="M">hbase-server.src.main.java.org.apache.hadoop.hbase.regionserver.HRegion.java</file>
    </fixedFiles>
  </bug>
</bugrepository>
